<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>One New Universe</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Welcome to One New Universe!</title><link href="/welcome-to-one-new-universe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>saurav</name></author><id>tag:,2016-01-15:welcome-to-one-new-universe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to One New Universe, powered by  &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. In this Universe, we
will mostly talk about data and what they can tell us about the social
and physical construct we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;
My blogging life has gone through several
incarnations, almost entirely consisting of blog hosting sites. My
needs are slightly different now. So are my wants for control of my
blog. I needed a platform that would support markdown (including
syntax highlighting for code and LaTeX rendering) and Jupyter
notebooks. I wanted a platform where I could write in plain text,
rather than in the GUIs that most blogging sites demand. Pelican is a
python-based static site generator that cleanly separates the content from the page
environment seamlessly. I used a custom perl script to write
several websites, including mine, in graduate school, so this feels
like coming back home. Since the
content lives on my hard drive as plain text, I am free to host or
move it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend Pelican to anyone. It needs a basic
understanding of python and coding. To set it up, I used  two
excellent setup guides: &lt;a href="http://www.notionsandnotes.org/tech/web-development/pelican-static-blog-setup.html"&gt;
Notions and Notes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/jakevdp/PythonicPerambulations"&gt;
Pythonic Perambulations&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to explore some fun ideas. Come along for the ride …&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>